Bilguun Zorigtbaatar

Software Test Automation Engineer – Software Engineer

- Fairfax, VA
- Email: bilguinzorigt07@gmail.com
- (703) 474-6342
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bilguun-zorigtbaatar/
- Website: bilguun-zorig.github.io/app

Dedicated IT professional with 8+ years of experience providing. Experienced in Software Quality Assurance Testing, proficient in testing web-based applications, and experience in Selenium. I am passionate about Software Development, where I enjoy evaluating products from different angles and expectations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Testing Tools	Selenium WebDriver, Postman, SQL
Build Tool	Maven
Test Framework	TestNG, Junit, Data Driven Framework & Cucumber BDD
Devos Framework	Flask, Spring Boot, MERN
Languages	Java, JavaScript (ES6+), Python
Frontend	HTML, CSS, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Jinja2, JSP, Mongoose
Backend	Node.JS, Express.JS, MySQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, RESTful
	API, Oracle SQL
Tools	Git, GitHub, npm, Visual Studio Code, Jira
Operating System	Windows & IOS

PROJECTS

BooBoo Boo Github

BooBoo is Book listing website. This web application is built on MERN: MongoDB, Express.js, React, and Node.js.

- Utilized Bootstrap is used to create a responsive website that allows users to browse the website on different tools.
- Designed RESTful backend routes to allow quick lookup of user and track information for a smooth user experience.
- Implemented a comprehensive user authentication system using JWT to secure user data and sessions.
- Integrated an advanced search functionality allowing users to filter books by genre, author, and rating.
- Created user profiles enabling book tracking, review, submissions, and personalized recommendations.

MyRecipes <u>Demo Video | Github</u>

MyRecipes is a web application built using Flask, Python, and MySQL, leveraging a comprehensive recipe dataset The dataset includes over 180,000 recipes and 700,000 recipes reviews, covering 18 years of user interactions. The app allows users to search for recipes by ingredients for specific meals.

- Utilized Bootstrap is used to create a responsive website that allows users to browse the website on different tools.
- Designed RESTful backend routes to allow quick lookup of user and track information for a smooth user experience.
- Implemented an advanced search feature that enables users to find recipes by ingredients, catering to specific meal preferences.
- Integrated a user review system where users can rate and review recipes, providing valuable feedback to others.
- Developed a feature for users to save favorite recipes and create custom meal plans.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

QA Automation Engineer Farm Credit Bank of Texas

Jan 2022 – present

- Involved in building automation framework from scratch using Selenium WebDriver, and Cucumber (BDD).
- Experienced in Cross Browser Testing by executing test cases in Firefox, Chrome, and Internet Explorer.
- Utilize CSS selectors, IDs, and XPaths to locate elements on Web pages.
- Performed BDD (Behavior Driven Development) using Cucumber Features, Scenarios, and Step Definitions in Gherkin format.
- Used Maven for build management, and Jenkins for Continuous Integration of the builds.
- Assessed and analyzed user stories and participated in Sprint planning, Review Sessions & Scrum Meetings, and developed Test scenarios, Test cases, Test data, Test procedures, Test reports.
- Performed UI, Functional, and Regression testing by automated using Selenium WebDriver, Cucumber, Maven, and Jenkins.
- Developed Automation framework implementing Page Object Model, using JAVA, Selenium Web Driver, and Cucumber.
- Used Selenium WebDriver to run test cases in multiple browsers and cross Platforms.
- Integrated Automation scripts (Selenium WebDriver API) in Continuous Integration tools (Jenkins) for nightly consignment run of the Script.
- Assisted in managing and updating Requirements Tracking tool.
- Support test and technical teams involved in developing requirements and software design artifacts to ensure familiarity with the requirements and expected functionality of the system.
- Maintains necessary level of communication with team members and other support groups and does so in a participative management style, conducive with operational goals.
- Develop performance test plans and cases including an automated test scenario and environment for performance testing.
- Log defects, creating defect reports, and conducting regression testing.
- Performed API testing using Postman and RestAssured, including validating JSON and XML responses, and testing RESTful web services.

QA Lead Automation Engineer *TechCircle Solutions*, *LLC*

Jan 2019 – 2022

- Instructed on industry-standard tools and technologies such as Selenium WebDriver, JUnit, TestNG, and Cucumber for automated testing.
- Design and implement comprehensive test plans to ensure that systems and software behave as expected and meet customer requirements.
- Write test plans, create test cases/ scenarios, executing manual or automated test scripts, generate test results, analyze test results, and coordinate with the development teams for bug fixes
- Utilized CSS selectors, IDs, and XPaths to locate elements on Web pages.
- Log defects, creating defect reports, and conducting regression testing.
- Developed framework using Cucumber, Junit, TestNG, Page Object Model, Page Factory.
- Worked closely with developers to assign proper object identifications properties for web objects to solve the object recognition issue in Selenium WebDriver.
- Created SQL Queries and performed back-end testing to check compared UI and the database.
- Performed API testing using Postman and RestAssured, including validating JSON and XML responses, and testing RESTful web services.

- Participated in test cases review meetings with the testing team and provided input to the test cases.
- Prepared weekly test execution status report and presented in weekly status meetings.
- Developed BDD tests using Cucumber by writing behaviors and step definitions. Developed required Selenium support code in JAVA for Cucumber.
- Assisted QA lead in documenting User Acceptance Test reports and reporting defect resolution.
- Responsible for identifying test cases for Smoke Test, Functional, and Regression Tests.

QA Automation Engineer

Petco, Inc

Sep 2017 – Jan 2019

- Involved in Test Design, Test plan and preparing Test Results for each executed component.
- Designed and developed positive and negative test cases using Selenium WebDriver and executed based on functional requirements.
- Design, develop, implement, and maintain Behavior Driven Development (BDD) automation testing framework utilizing Selenium Web-Driver, Java, Cucumber and Maven.
- Responsible for creating Integration, System, Regression and UAT test cases and test execution of functional features.
- Responsible for analyzing and prioritizing functional, regression test cases for test automation development.
- Designed and Implemented Hybrid Framework in Eclipse for Functional and Regression test cases with JAVA.
- Automated Smoke Test, Functional and Regression test cases in Selenium WebDriver, Perfecto Driver with Descriptive Programming and Custom Functions.
- Developed proper exception handling strategies in Selenium WebDriver and Perfecto Driver to improve the test script efficiency with Java.
- Developed framework using Cucumber, Junit, TestNG, Page Object Model, Page Factory.
- Maintained Test Resources, test data, Maven Dependencies, Test Configuration Files and XML POM File in Eclipse for test automation team collaboration.
- Executed manual and automated test cases, analyzed the execution result, and logged Defect in Jira.
- Developed functions in JAVA Programming Language to capture UI data and compared it with expected results using Page Object Model.
- Responsible for developing, maintaining, and executing daily Smoke Test Script in multiple testing environments to check the application stability.
- Worked closely with developers to assign proper object identifications properties for web objects to solve the object recognition issue in Selenium WebDriver.
- Performed API testing using Postman and RestAssured, including validating JSON and XML responses, and testing RESTful web services.
- Created SQL Queries and performed back-end testing to check compared UI and the database.
- Participated in test cases review meetings with the testing team and provided input to the test cases.
- Prepared weekly test execution status report and presented in weekly status meetings.
- Developed BDD tests using Cucumber by writing behaviors and step definitions. Developed required Selenium support code in JAVA for Cucumber.

EDUCATION

University of the Potomac, School of Business

Master of Business Administration in Marketing (MBA)

June 2020

- **Concentration:** Marketing Manager
- **GPA:** 3.90/4.00, graduated with distinction.

Coding Dojo

Washington, DC

Washington, DC

Computer Software Engineering – Triple Black Belt

Dec 2023

- Achieved the highest level of knowledge achievement on all 3 curriculums.
- Built, tested, and deployed 3 full stack projects in Python Jinja, Java Spring Boot and JavaScript MERN

Washington University of Science and Technology (WUEST) **Master of Science in Information Technology (MSIT)**

Washington, DC

2022 to present

- Concentration: Software Design and Management.
- **GPA:** 3.90/4.00.